翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
Welcome to Data Structures.
欢迎学习数据结构
If you're watching this, you're probably somebody enrolled in the actual physical class at Berkeley, CS61B.
视频前的你可能在线下参加了伯克利的 CS61B 课程
But if you're just some random person from the internet, you're welcome too.
又或者你只是互联网上的某个学生，我们同样欢迎你
All the material will be here available on the web for you to learn.
你可以在网络上找到这门课程的所有材料
Everything's free.
并且它们完全免费
So hop in. So what is this class?
让我们开始吧，那么这门课讲授什么呢？
Well, this is a second semester class, as most of you at Berkeley know.
伯克利的很多学生都知道，这是第二学期的课程
And it is to me one of the most important classes.
对我来说，这是最重要的课程之一
I'm a little biased, because this is my baby and the class I spent the most time developing and thinking about.
可能我说得有点偏激，因为这门课就像我的孩子，花费了我很多心血
But this is the class where you go from being a basic programmer, knowing how to build stuff,
但是这门课会带领你从一个基本的程序员，成长到知道如构建东西
and really working your way towards independence.
直至朝着独立的方向发展
It's kind of like boot camp.
有点新兵训练营的意思
This is the class where when you leave it, I want you to be able to walk into say Google or Airbnb, do an internship, blow people's minds, do well.
课程结束后，我希望你能够去 Google 或者 Airbnb 实习，并且优秀得让他们大吃一惊
This is the class where when you're done, I want you to think OK, there's some thing I want to achieve.
课程结束后，我也希望你可以实现自己的想法
Maybe I want to learn to build an Android app to, I don't know, connect children in countries
比如说学着构建一款将各国孩子联系在一起的 Android app
so they can compare Pokemon or whatever,
他们可以通过 app 比较宝可梦之类的
whatever It may be that you want to build.
或者是任何你想构建的东西
This is the class where I want you to get the independence and the skills necessary to go out there and do anything else that you want to do.
也就是说，我想让你学会独立和必要的技能去做任何你想做的事
The great unlocking of all things out there.
开启世间万物的大门
So how are we going to do that? What is the framework of this going to be?
那么我们要怎么做呢？这门课的框架是什么样呢？
Well, this class is fundamentally about efficiency.
基本上讲，这门课是关于效率的
And it will connect us to this notion of independence as we'll see in a moment.
稍后会看到，它把我们与独立的概念联系起来
So the first way in which we might consider efficiency is in our programs themselves.
我们考虑效率的第一点可能就是程序本身
How long does it take the computer to run the program?
计算机运行这个程序需要多长时间？
How much memory does the program use?
这个程序使用了多少内存？
And to understand that we're going to study a certain set of algorithms
为了理解这一点，我们将研究一些算法
that are really good ways of solving certain problems.
这些算法可以很好地解决上述问题
And data structures, ways of keeping our information organized so it can be rapidly retrieved and modified and so forth.
数据结构同样关键，它们可以有条理地组织信息以供快速搜索和修改等
So that'll be an important goal.
所以（程序效率高）这个目标很重要
But arguably more important is learning to be yourself a more efficient programmer,
但更重要的是学会成为一名高效的程序员
to spend less time to build the same complexity of program.
构建同样复杂的程序时花费更少的时间
And so to do that we are going to along the way we're going to learn to design, build, test,
为了实现这一点，我们将一步一步学习设计、构建、测试
and debug large programs, over 1,000 lines or so.
以及调试超过1000行的大型程序
And what that's going to do is give you an opportunity to approach a specific problem and really beat your head against the wall a little
你将有机会去解决具体的棘手到想撞墙的问题
and think about all the different trade-off that might go into how you might design a program.
并且需要考虑程序设计中的各种取舍
So in previous classes you've probably mostly been given a set of functions you fill in.
在之前的课程（CS61A）中，你可能学会如何实现一些函数
That will not be the case for much of this class.
但这门课不限于此
Along the way, we'll also learn to use a set of programming tools.
我们还将学习使用一些编程工具
We're going to use a bunch of real world tools, principally git, IntelliJ and JUnit.
这些工具在现实中广泛使用，以 Git、IntelliJ 和 JUnit 为代表
And we're going to learn Java as we go.
我们同时要学习 Java
Now Java is not the goal of the class. This is not a Java programming class.
不过这是次要的，这不是 Java 编程课
We just needed a language which is popular and is used for large scale programs, and it is both of those things.
我们只是需要一种流行的、用于大规模程序的语言，它可能是 Java 和 Python
But it could have been other languages.
也可能是其他语言
And we're not really going to focus on Java so much, though we'll have to at the beginning just to get up to speed.
因此尽管为了跟上进度我们必须在一开始介绍 Java，但并不打算耗费很多精力
So this class assumes you already have a fairly solid programming foundation.
所以本门课假设你已经具备了扎实的编程基础
That you know what object oriented programming is and you've done, say class definition,
你需要知道什么是面向对象编程并且动手完成了一些实现，比如类的定义
that you know recursion, that you've dealt with lists and trees.
你需要知道递归，操作过 List 和 Tree
And we're going to build from that.
我们将以此为基础
So why is it that if we're going to try and learn to be independent programmers,
那么为了学习成为独立的程序员
why specifically are we focusing on data structures and algorithms?
为什么我们要重点关注数据结构和算法呢？
Why isn't this say, an Android app development class or a robotics class?
为什么不是 Android 应用程序开发课程或是机器人课程呢？
Well for me, data structures and algorithms are particularly interesting and very general class of problems that have all kinds of neat stuff to them.
因为对我而言，数据结构和算法特别有趣，而且可以用各种巧妙的方法解决普遍问题
So one of them, of course, is that our daily life is only possible because of really advanced algorithms and data structures.
比如其中一个日常生活中的问题，要依靠真正先进的算法和数据结构
So of course, if we open up-- let's see, I'll do another Google tab here.
我们打开...我新建一个谷歌标签页
We know auto complete.
我们都知道自动补全功能
And we know that it seems to work well.
而且它似乎运行得特别稳定
But it happens so seamlessly we don't even think about it.
万无一失以至我们甚至没有察觉
So we might do something like "how does auto complete work?"
那么我们搜索，比方说“自动补全是如何工作的？”
OK, hey. And you'll notice that as I'm typing like "what are snails good for?"
好，你会注意到当我输入“蜗牛有什么好处？”
Whatever. "What are snails even trying to do?"
哈哈管他呢，“蜗牛到底想干什么？”
That is a good question. Let's see, what are they trying to do?
这是个好问题，让我看看他们想做什么？
Well, you can read later.
算了，晚点再看吧
I bet there's some good stuff in there.
这里面肯定有不少好东西
Anyway, we can see that as we're typing that the Google search box here, it responds instantly.
不管怎样，我们可以看到当我们在谷歌搜索框输入时，它会立即响应
Like how is auto-- yeah. Or whatever it may be. It just happened instantly.
就像“如何自动...”，无论输入什么，自动补全都会立刻发生
As soon as I press a button, boom.
我一按下按钮就发生了
And that is enabled only because they're using the right data structures and algorithms.
这仅仅是因为他们使用了正确的数据结构和算法
And in fact, at the very tail end of this course we'll talk about the specific data structures used to support this.
事实上，在本课程的最后我们将讨论实现这一功能的数据结构
Another big thing is that algorithms and data structures are really driving what's changing in our lives right now.
另一件重要的事情是，算法和数据结构实际上正在改变我们的生活
So here is a Google self-driving car prototype.
这是一个谷歌自动驾驶汽车的原型
So Google, Uber, other companies are really pushing hard, and Tesla, of course, are really pushing hard on building cars that drive themselves.
谷歌、优步和其他公司都在努力制造自动驾驶汽车，当然还有特斯拉
And that's going to have just insane implications.
这将会产生疯狂的影响
Like millions of jobs in the United States are going to disappear in the near term.
比如美国短期内将消失数以百万计的就业机会
Something like a million or so people a year are killed in car accidents around the world.
又比如全世界每年大约有一百万人死于车祸
And so we're going to see just tremendous upheaval as these become state of art.
当智能驾驶成为现实，这一状况将会发生巨大的转变
And it's the algorithms and the data structures used to store all the information that as this car is learning they allow this to happen,
因此是算法和数据结构存储了所有的信息，使这辆车不断学习
to be able to make these big changes in our lives.
以至能够改变我们的生活
Another, of course, is well data structures, it turns out, having a good handle on them is perhaps the most important thing for being a good programmer.
另外，事实证明，良好地掌握数据结构可能是成为一名优秀程序员最重要的事情
So the creator of Linux, Linus Torvalds says,
就像 Linux 的创建者 Linus Torvalds 说的那样
"the difference between a bad programmer and a good one is whether the programmer considers code or data structures more important. Bad programmers worry about the code."
“烂程序员关心的是代码，好程序员关心的是数据结构和它们之间的关系”
You know, what does it look like?
你应该知道这是什么意思
Do you use tabs or spaces or something like that.
您是否使用制表符或空格或类似的东西
"Good programmers worry about data structures and their relationships."
“优秀的程序员关心数据结构和它们之间的关系 ”
And you'll see this when we get the project two.
你拿到项目二时会理解这一点
If you make the right choices about the data structures you need to implement this database system,
实现数据库系统时如果你选择了正确的数据结构
then you'll have a much easier time.
那任务就变得轻松多了
But if you make bad calls about the class hierarchy or about how you're storing information,
但是如果你对类的层次结构或存储信息的方式做出了错误的判断
your life will be much more difficult.
你的日子不会好过的
And we'll see that again in great detail in a few weeks.
我们将在几周内再次详细阐释这一理念
Another reason that this is a fun topic is just for intellectual stimulation.
另一个有趣的原因是智力激发
This has a lot a neat little math problems.
这里面有很多数学题
I don't know if you've ever tried to draw this house.
我不知道你有没有尝试画过这座房子
So the goal is put down your pencil in a corner and then try and draw the house without picking up your pencil.
从一个角落开始，不抬起笔画完整个房子
So maybe I go there, there, there, there, there, there.
比如我可以这样
Uh-oh, I missed a line.
哎呀，我漏了一条线
I mean, you couldn't tell because you couldn't see me drawing, but try it out.
你可能没看到我刚才画的，但你可以试一试
So it turns out it is possible to draw this house without picking up your pencil.
不拿起笔画出这座房子
However, it is not possible to cross these seven bridges in this town without having to basically hop.
另一道题中，不经过跳跃无法经过小镇上的七座桥
You can't do the equivalent of drawing the house over here.
这个道理跟画房子类似
And so there it turns out you might ask yourself, why is that?
所以你可能会问这是为什么呢？
And just from a mathematical perspective, I'm just curious.
仅从数学角度分析，这令人好奇
Why can you draw this house? Why can you not draw this? Is there some simple rule?
你为什么可以画这座房子？你又为什么不能画那个呢？有规则可循吗？
Turns out there is, and we'll talk a little bit about graph theory later in this class.
事实证明就是这样的，我们将在课程后面的图论部分讨论它
And so if that's an aspect of computer science you find interesting, that is theory,
因此，如果你对计算机科学中的一个方面——理论感兴趣
this is a class where you'll get a little taste of theory as well.
这门课也能满足你的需求
Another big reason we're curious about algorithms and data structures is that if we can develop--
算法和数据结构另一个有趣的原因是，如果我们能够开发...
so it's important in the modern scientific world to be able to program.
在现代科学界，编程是很重要的能力
It's important to be able to know what algorithms are out there, what appropriate data structures you need to write simulations.
重要的是知道有哪些算法，编写仿真需要哪些合适的数据结构
Because that's the direction science has gone.
因为这是科学发展的方向
And so one interesting example here on the left.
左边有一个有趣的例子
This is a video of starlings flying around. They're a type of bird.
视频中的八哥（一种鸟）飞来飞去
And this is a simulation on the right showing that we're able to recapitulate the essential behavior of this flock.
右边是相应的仿真，概括了这群鸟的基本行为
And so you can do fun things where you start sending, say there is a hawk chasing them around.
你可以做一些有趣的事情，比方说有一只鹰在周围追赶它们
Here I guess you can't quite see the hawk.
鹰在这里，你应该看不到它
Because of the fact that we write a simple model that's able to demonstrate this same behavior,
因为我们写了一个简单的模型来模拟同样的行为
it implies that we know something important, potentially, about how these birds are behaving.
这意味着我们可能知道一些关于这些鸟类行为的重要信息
And this is also used in other areas like in protein folding and galaxy formation.
其他领域同样适用，比如蛋白质的折叠和星系的形成
All across the board, simulation is a really important tool.
总的来说，仿真是一个非常重要的工具
And not just in terms of understanding and proving to yourself that you know how the universe works,
不仅有助于理解证实宇宙的运转
but you can imagine also maybe this algorithm the bird is using could actually be useful for some real world application,
而且这些鸟正在使用的算法可能会对现实应用有用
say I don't know, swarming flying drones or something.
我不确定，也许是成群飞行的无人机
Another nice thing about algorithms and data structures is that with really good knowledge of them,
很好地了解算法和数据结构的另一件益处是
even if you're say in this only for the aesthetics, only for art, there's some neat things you can do.
即便只专于美学和艺术，你还是可以做一些奇妙的事情
So here are some realistic fluid simulations using some clever fluid dynamics algorithms.
这里有一个使用流体力学算法的真实仿真
I like the soundtrack.
配乐很棒
It's just really exciting bullion cubes.
这些金块令人兴奋
That's all simulation.
这些全部是模拟出来的
But they can build lots of really cool stuff, obviously, with fluid simulations like this.
不过显而易见，这样的流体仿真可以制造很多有趣的东西
Another particularly beautiful thing.
还有一个特别漂亮的东西
Oh, before I get there.
对了，我插一嘴
So for my students at Berkeley, I just want to throw out there that
我想告诉我在伯克利的学生
if you like watching fluids flow like those simulations, nature's best fluid flow show, the ocean.
如果你喜欢像刚才仿真那样的流体流动，自然界最好的代表就是海洋
You may not realize that living in the Bay Area that waves get really, really big.
可能你没有意识到，旧金山湾区的海浪特别大
So on January 21st there will be some 35 foot waves.
1月21日将会有大约35英尺（约10米）的海浪
Maybe go to the beach and check those out.
或许到时候你该去海滩看看
But back to computer science.
回到计算机科学上来
Another rather beautiful thing here is of course, recently,
最近发生的另一个特别出色的事情是
Go playing computers have done well.
围棋电脑取得了不错的成绩
The AlphaGo beat the world's best players.
AlphaGo 击败了世界上最好的棋手
Totally swept the entire tournament and even beat the world's reigning champion.
横扫了整个锦标赛，甚至击败了世界卫冕冠军
And I really like this quote from the reigning Go champion.
我真的很喜欢这位围棋卫冕冠军的话
And "after humanity spent thousands of years improving tactics, computers have told us that humans are completely wrong."
“人类数千年的实战演练进化，计算机却告诉我们人类全都是错的 ”
That is we cannot compete.
这意味着我们难以竞争
So it's interesting about the way that this Go computer played is it played unlike a human.
有趣的是，这台围棋电脑下棋的思维方式与人类不同
It did weird stuff and it still managed to win.
它有时下法很奇怪，但还是赢下了比赛
And so the reigning Go champion said.
正如这位围棋卫冕冠军所说
"I would go as far as to say not a single human has touched the edge of the truth of Go."
“我觉得，甚至没有一个人沾到围棋真理的边 ”
So leave it to a Go player to say something really poignant and beautiful, you know, poetry just from your profession.
留下了围棋棋手口中那些辛酸又美丽的话，那是职业中的诗歌
Good job. Now not everybody's impressed.
说得好，但并不是每个人都印象深刻
There was a guy in the internet comments section who said
互联网评论区有个人说
"The rules of Go are quite simple and the resources that you have out there for learning it are gigantic. And no one was surprised except for poorly educated losers."
“围棋规则非常简单，学习资源又十分丰富
除了受教育程度较低的失败者，没有人对此感到惊讶 ”
So I don't know. Internet comments section, they disagree.
我不确定，可能互联网评论区不同意
But I still think it's beautiful even if this guy doesn't.
虽然这家伙不喜欢，但我仍然觉得它很出色
And lastly, another big reason that we might study algorithms and data structures is
最后，研究算法和数据结构的另一个重要原因是
well, it sure seems like a popular thing for people my age to be doing.
对我这个年龄的人来说，这似乎是一件很受欢迎的事情
So at Berkeley, most of the students here, you know, are largely 18 to 21, not everybody.
伯克利的大多数学生是18~21岁
And it seems like everybody else, you know, people who look like us, we're all doing this thing. It must be important.
除此之外几乎所有人，比如我，都在研究它，重要性显而易见
This year, the 61B total enrollment for data structures is going to be we're estimating just shy of 2,000 students.
今年，CS61B 的总注册人数将接近2000
We currently have 1,350 enrolled.
目前已经有1350人注册
I anticipate we'll have 1,250 at week four.
估计第四周会有1250个
So this is the entire history of 61B's enrollment.
这是 CS61B 注册的历史数据
And you can see here this is the dot-com boom and then the crash that followed.
你可以看到，这时是互联网的繁荣期，然后是紧随其后的崩盘
Now even the dot-com boom, which was a big deal at the time,
现在来看，即使在这个惊动当时的繁荣期
we're completely annihilating the enrollments at that time period.
报名的人数也与今天相差较大
And in fact, if you think of the post boom period,
事实上，与后繁荣时期对比
the number of students currently enrolled this semester, spring 2017, is 1,250,
本学期（2017年春季）目前招收的学生为1250人
which is the equivalent of everybody in the years 2004 through 2007 combined.
这相当于2004到2007年间所有人的总和
So that's pretty amazing.
所以这是相当令人惊讶的
So there's something in the water. You guys are going nuts for computer science and data structures in particular.
你们一定是被下药了，对计算机科学特别是数据结构如此着谜
So hey, social proof.
事实就是这样
So that's the story. That's why I like algorithms and data structures.
这就是故事的来龙去脉，也是我喜欢算法和数据结构的原因
And I think this class I hope you'll find is just a really good introduction to being independent,
我希望你们会发现这门课是一个让你走向独立的课程
being able to build all these beautiful things from self-driving cars up to Go playing robots.
从智能驾驶到围棋电脑，你能构建以上所有美好的东西
There's plenty more you'll need to learn, especially if you're doing AI.
可能还要有很多东西要学习，特别是想从事人工智能
You'll have to learn lots and lots about state of the art algorithms for those specific areas later.
之后你不得不学习大量有关这些特定领域最先进的算法知识
But this here is the foundation of independence.
但这里是独立的基础
So I would ask you who you were, but you're watching a video.
我想知道你是谁，但你正在看视频
So you could maybe talk to the screen yourself and explain who you are and pretend that I'm listening.
所以你可以自己对着屏幕向我介绍，我假装在听
I'll pretend like I'm listening.
我会假装我在听
OK, good. Good to meet you.
好的，很高兴见到你
Sorry I couldn't actually meet you. It would be super cool.
抱歉没能真正见到你，但你一定很有趣
I would really like to be able to divide my consciousness into like, I don't know, thousands or hundreds of thousands of copies and talk to everybody.
我真的希望能够将我的意识分成千百万份，然后与每个人交谈
Sadly, can't do it.
可惜我做不到
So a little bit about us.
下面稍微介绍一下我们的情况
So this semester, the spring '17 staff if you are an enrolled student, there's me.
本学期（17年春季）的课程由我教授
I'm Josh Hug, by the way. I'm a teacher professor here at Berkeley.
顺便说一下，我是 Josh Hug，一名伯克利的教授
I have an office in the building. You can email me.
我在楼里有一间办公室，你可以发给我发邮件
And this is my fourth time teaching this class, second time doing this version of the class.
这是我第四次教这门课，第二次教这个版本
And here all the teaching assistants.
所有的助教都在这里
And in addition to all these teaching assistants who I won't even name because there are so many,
除了所有这些助教之外，我想念他们的名字，实在太多了
we also have a bunch of tutors who will be there to help people out who need a little extra help.
我们还有一群导师，他们会帮助有其他需要的人
We'll talk more about that later in the semester.
我们将在本学期晚些时候详细讨论这一点
And then we have a bunch of lab assistants, AKA, academic interns, which number around 140.
我们还有一群实验室助理，也就是学术实习生，大约有140人
Who are volunteers, so thank you.
他们是志愿者，感谢你们
None of them are here so you can't meet them because I'm just at my house.
他们都不在这里，所以你不能见他们，因为这里是我家
But that's that.
好了
Now I mentioned, by the way, in case you're curious,
顺便说一句，如果你好奇的话
you can look at-- I did, since there are so many of them, I was curious, what is the letter distribution of the names here versus English?
你可以看看...我做了这个，因为人数太多了，我很好奇名字和名字字母的分布是怎样？
I won't talk about it here in this video.
在视频里我不会过多介绍
But hey, kind of fun. All right, for me it was.
不过我觉得真的挺有意思的
So that said, we're going to talk soon about the way that you learn
接下来我们会讨论你们学习的方式
and what in the course you can use to gain additional knowledge.
以及在这门课程中怎样获得额外的知识
And I like this little example,
我喜欢这个小例子
because I, as somebody who grew up when I was a kid I had adults always telling me like you're super good at math or whatever.
因为我从小长大的过程中，大人们总是夸奖我数学或其他方面超级好
And I didn't really understand that practice makes you get good at things.
但我没有真正体会到熟能生巧
And in fact, the thing that taught me that-- this is embarrassing to admit-- is Dance, Dance, Revolution.
事实上，教会我这个道理的是...有点尴尬...是跳舞机
So those of you who are not familiar, Dance, Dance Revolution is a game where music plays and you step on these arrows.
可能有人不熟悉这个游戏，你需要根据音乐踩下对应的箭头
And these are some beginning players.
这边是一些新手
And you can see, you know, this is where we all start out as programmers.
就像你所看到的，我们程序员最初也是这样
On the right here, this is somebody who has a little more practice.
右边的这个人要有经验得多
And so long ago I had a job where I had nothing to do and I would just go to lunch for an hour and a half every day or something like that and play Dance, Dance Revolution.
很久以前，我有一份清闲的工作，每天吃饭午饭就去玩跳舞机
I didn't quite get to this level of good, but I got pretty close.
我没有这么好的水平，但十分接近
And that was actually a really important moment for me because I realized, you know what?
这件事对我来说很有意义，因为我意识到
That's actually how people get good at things.
这实际上就是人们变得善于做事的方法
And so right now you may be here, but ultimately I want to get you here.
所以现在你可能在这里，但最终我想把你带到这里
And I think that after you finish the whole computer science program,
我认为当你完成整个计算机科学课程后
even if you're somebody who to this point has thought like, am I really good at that?
也许你此刻还在思考，我真的会擅长吗？
Because it can be really intimidating to be in a room full of people who have been programming, you know, for a decade.
确实，呆在充满编程超过十年的人的房间令人生畏
You know, you're 18 and they've been doing it since they were eight, to feel like could I ever possibly compete.
你18岁了，他们可能从8岁起就开始学习了，你怀疑是否还能竞争
But really you can.
但你真的可以
Now, it is, of course, true that people with more background and people who have learned to think in a certain way,
当然了，有的人背景和思考方式更好一些
they're going to learn more quickly than you.
他们会比你学得更快
But the important point here is that I really think that the ceiling,
但重要的是，而且我坚信
that if you had a year to really spend on this class, and especially if you're somebody out there on the internet.
如果花费一年的时间在这门课上，尤其是如果你是互联网上的某个人
If you're in the middle of nowhere, I mean, great, glad you're here.
可能你在一个偏僻的地方，很高兴你来到这里
I think you can really get super good at this,
我认为你真的可以在这方面做得超级好
even if you feel like you're somebody who hasn't been a natural at this, right.
即便你觉得自己没有天分
Being a natural, whatever that may mean, sure it helps you learn faster.
天赋确实会帮助你更快的学习
But the point is that with practice I'm pretty sure anybody, almost anybody can get up to about this level.
但重点是，我非常肯定通过练习几乎任何人都能达到这个水平
So how do you learn?
那么你该如何学习的呢？
Well, you'll learn a little bit watching these videos.
你会从视频中学到一些东西
Now especially if you're somebody who's just watching the videos online,
特别是如果你只是在网上看视频
watching me talk is maybe vaguely entertaining and you'll get an introduction to the new material.
看着我讲话可能还挺有意思的，而且会有新材料的介绍
But this is only a small minority of the manner in which learning occurs.
但这只是课程学习中的一小部分
Same deal with reading. Like just sitting there and reading the online text you'll get stuff out of it.
阅读也是如此，比如只是坐在那里阅读在线文本，你会从中学到一些东西
But really where stuff happens is when you yourself are actually programming.
但真正有所变化的是你自己实际在编程的时候
Learning is seeing a problem, figuring out a way to approach it,
学习就是发现问题，找出问题的解决方法
hitting a brick wall often, and then finding a way over that brick wall.
经常碰壁，然后想办法翻过那堵墙
So in this class during the labs, the homework, and experimenting on your own will give you a chance to learn all the basics.
所以这门课的实验、作业以及你自己的尝试将会学习基础
Say Java syntax, learn a little bit about algorithms and data structures, and get a chance to learn the tools for this class.
比如说 Java 语法、一些算法和数据结构、本课程的工具
If you are a Berkeley student, you will also have discussion section
如果你是伯克利的学生，你会有一个讨论区
where you'll get a chance to practice with the concepts and argue about approaches to problems.
在那里你将有机会练习概念或讨论解决问题的方法
And then we'll have these big projects, which are going to be similar to the labs and homeworks.
我们还会有些大型项目，类似于实验和作业
They're going to be programming oriented, but we're going to have a design component.
它们需要编程实现，但多了一个设计环节
And we're typically going to have these big systems building challenges.
我们要经常面临这些大型系统构建的挑战
These will also involve writing of tests, whereas for labs and homeworks we'll typically give you all of those.
包括测试的编写，而实验和作业通常会提供所有测试
This is where you're going to learn lots of stuff.
这部分你将学到很多东西
So we'll talk about course logistics in this next little segment.
我们将在下一小节中讨论课程安排
But I just want to say, this class, it is really truly about making you into hopefully a great programmer.
但在此之前我想说，这门课真的会让你成为一名优秀的程序员
And I believe that even if you're somebody who is maybe
并且我相信即使你是一个...
say I don't know, even a C student in your previous programming course,
比方说我不确定，你只在之前的编程课中拿到了 C 级
if you maybe not this semester, maybe you don't have enough time to catch up.
也许这学期你没有足够的时间追赶上
But really if you are sentient and you enjoy this and you are even able to get the--
但是只要有心，你足够喜欢，你总会...
if you were even able to digest the basics of programming, you can actually get really good at this,
如果你能够消化编程的基础知识，你真的可以很擅长它
but it may take a lot of practice.
但这可能需要大量的练习
So that's that. We'll move onto course logistics next.
那就这样了，接下来我们来讲讲课程安排
翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
And see you in that video.
下个视频见吧